astro.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy - Astrodienst

### Privacy Policy of www.astro.com / Astrodienst AG / Astro AG

**About the information you give us**

Astrodienst has been serving its customers around the world since 1980\. Those customers entrust us with information which they expect to remain confidential. We take that trust seriously. The information you provide to Astrodienst is not made available to any other company or individual. It is used internally to process the orders you place with us, whether for a free service or when you are making a purchase.

**Protection of personal data**

Astrodienst has its own servers which are maintained by us. Nobody outside of Astrodienst has access to our software or data. The website uses encryption (TLSv.1.2) for security and to protect the transmission of confidential content. You can recognize an encrypted connection by the fact that the address line of the browser changes from "http://" to "https://" and by the lock symbol in your browser line. All pages that transmit personal data to our servers are encrypted in secure TLS mode. The data that you transmit to us cannot be read by third parties.

As the controller, the Astrodienst AG has implemented numerous technical and organizational measures to ensure the most complete protection of personal data processed through this website. However, Internet-based data transmissions may in principle have security gaps, so absolute protection may not be guaranteed. For this reason, every data subject is free to transfer personal data to us via alternative means, e.g. by telephone. 

**Collection of personal data**

If we require personal information from you, you will be asked to confirm that your details have been transmitted. By submitting your data you give us your consent to collect this data. In general, this data is requested when you create a horoscope, create a registered user profile or purchase a product from the AstroShop.

**Use of personal data**

The creation of a horoscope on our website requires the entry of birth data: time, date and place of birth, as well as at least one first name, which can also be a pseudonym.

  * The use of the services on this website is possible with an anonymous guest profile, which does not require any personal data other than birth data for the horoscope.

To create a registered user profile, the following data is recorded:

  * Your e-mail address, which also serves as your user name
  * Password
  * Title
  * Name and surname
  * Country
  * Language preferences

The following additional data is recorded for a purchase:

  * Address (complete postal address, postcode, city)
  * Phone number, Fax number (if any)
  * Your payment preferences, although we never have any knowledge of your credit card number
  * Any additional notifications you may have entered

Your personal data will be used for the following purposes:

  * To make it easier for you to use the website, you only need to enter your personal data once.
  * To deliver or activate a purchased product.
  * To ensure that only you have access to your chart data and online services.
  * In order to be able to invoice you when you make a purchase.

**Deletion of your data**

You can delete your data at any time in "My Astro", either individual birth data or the complete profile. Please note that when you delete a profile, any services such as subscriptions or E-horoscopes are also deleted and thus expire. You need your password to delete a registered user profile and the data it contains.

Deleting a profile does not mean that all data on the servers of Astrodienst is deleted. The data can no longer be accessed on the website, but will be stored for a period of six months before being irrevocably deleted. This is used to restore an erroneously deleted profile. If you wish to have your data deleted immediately and irrevocably, please contact us by email.

**Retention of data during an order**

The data that you transmit to us when placing an order is subject to retention due to our duty to preserve records. This period is 10 years for companies in Switzerland. All data relevant to an order - name, address, dates of birth, email, products, payment information etc. - will be stored by us during this period. This storage takes place independently of the website. This data cannot be deleted.  
Credit card data is never stored by Astrodienst, not even during the payment transaction, which is processed by an external payment provider. We never know your credit card number or security number.

**E-mails**

The services and contents of this website can be used anonymously and without registration. However, a registered user profile offers the possibility to store up to 100 birth data and to connect to your data from different devices. A valid email address is required to create a registered user profile. By creating a registered user profile, you give us permission to send you e-mails.

If you have forgotten your password or want to set a new one, the corresponding link will be sent to this address. We may also occasionally send you an email to this address informing you of the delivery status of a product you have requested, an innovation in a service you have requested or an innovation on the website, for example. It is not possible to use a registered user profile on www.astro.com and at the same time to cancel these emails completely, as they are regarded as an essential part of the service requested by you.

Your email address will be treated confidentially and will not be passed on to third parties.

We send out a few newsletters a year. Sending is done via our own servers. No personal tracking is carried out. Newsletters sent by us contain a link to unsubscribe from the mailing list.

**Use of cookies**

This website uses cookies. Cookies do not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain any viruses. Cookies serve to make our website more user-friendly, effective and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies". They are automatically deleted at the end of your visit. Other cookies remain stored on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to recognize your browser the next time you visit our website.

You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and only allow cookies in individual cases, exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally and activate the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. If you set your browser so that the website "www.astro.com" cannot set cookies, you can use our services, but we cannot guarantee that you will have access to data entered earlier. More about cookies at Astrodienst can be found in our FAQ.

**Forum posts**

The contributions in the Astro-Forum are public and accessible to everyone. Before publication, carefully check that they do not contain any information that is not intended for the public. Although we do not allow any search engines in the forum, you must expect that your contributions will be recorded by search engines that do not follow the rules and will also be accessible worldwide without specifically calling up our website. Deletion or correction of such search engine entries often cannot be enforced on foreign operators. Astrodienst has no claim to the deletion of this data. 

**Server Log Files**

Our server automatically collects and stores information in log files, which your browser automatically transmits to us. These are:

  * Browser type and browser version
  * operating system used
  * referrer URL
  * Host name of the accessing computer
  * Time of the server request

This data is not assigned to specific persons, and it is not combined with other data sources. We reserve the right to check the data subsequently if we become aware of concrete indications of an illegal use.

**Right to information, deletion, blocking**

You have the right to free information about your stored personal data, its origin and recipients, and the purpose of data processing as well as a right to correction, blocking or deletion of this data at any time. You can contact us at any time at the address given below if you have any further questions on the subject of personal data.

**Payment Method: Data protection provisions about the use of PayPal as a payment processor**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of PayPal. PayPal is an online payment service provider. Payments are processed via so-called PayPal accounts, which represent virtual private or business accounts. PayPal is also able to process virtual payments through credit cards when a user does not have a PayPal account. A PayPal account is managed via an e-mail address, which is why there are no classic account numbers. PayPal makes it possible to trigger online payments to third parties or to receive payments. PayPal also accepts trustee functions and offers buyer protection services.

The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg.

If the data subject chooses "PayPal" as the payment option in the online shop during the ordering process, we automatically transmit the data of the data subject to PayPal. By selecting this payment option, the data subject agrees to the transfer of personal data required for payment processing.

The personal data transmitted to PayPal is usually first name, last name, address, email address, IP address, telephone number, mobile phone number, or other data necessary for payment processing. The processing of the purchase contract also requires such personal data, which are in connection with the respective order.

The transmission of the data is aimed at payment processing and fraud prevention. The controller will transfer personal data to PayPal, in particular, if a legitimate interest in the transmission is given. The personal data exchanged between PayPal and the controller for the processing of the data will be transmitted by PayPal to economic credit agencies. This transmission is intended for identity and creditworthiness checks.

PayPal will, if necessary, pass on personal data to affiliates and service providers or subcontractors to the extent that this is necessary to fulfill contractual obligations or for data to be processed in the order.

The data subject has the possibility to revoke consent for the handling of personal data at any time from PayPal. A revocation shall not have any effect on personal data which must be processed, used or transmitted in accordance with (contractual) payment processing.

The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full.

**Facebook plugins**

Our pages include plugins from the social network Facebook, provider Facebook Inc, 4 Grand Canal Square D2 Dublin, Ireland. You can recognize the Facebook plugins by the Facebook logo on our page. An overview of the Facebook plugins can be found here: https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/.  
When you click on a "Share" button, a direct connection is established between your browser and the Facebook server. Facebook receives the information that you have visited our site with your IP address. If you click the Facebook "Share" button, content from our pages will be added to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate the visit to our pages with your user account. We would like to point out that, as the provider of the pages, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or of their use by Facebook. For more information, please see Facebook's Privacy Policy at https://www.facebook.com/policies

**Twitter**

Our pages include functions of the Twitter service. These functions are provided by Twitter Inc, 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. By using Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function, the websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and made known to other users. Data is also transmitted to Twitter. We would like to point out that, as the provider of the pages, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or how it is used by Twitter. For more information, please see Twitter's privacy policy at https://twitter.com/privacy. You can change your Twitter privacy settings in your account settings at: https://twitter.com/account/settings

**Google Analytics**

This website occasionally uses functions of the web analysis service Google Analytics. The provider is Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. The use of Google Analytics on www.astro.com is exclusively for statistical purposes. Astrodienst does not request or use any personalized data.  
Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there.  
You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en  
You can prevent Google Analytics from collecting your data by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie is set which prevents the collection of your data on future visits to this website: Disable Google Analytics

More information on how Google Analytics handles user data can be found in Google's privacy policy: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en

**Ads**

If you have purchased a horoscope or subscription from Astrodienst, the website will automatically be free of advertising for the duration of the subscription, or for 12 months (Astro*Intelligence-Horoscopes) or 6 months (all other horoscope interpretations). 

All other visitors receive advertisements. Most of them are placed by Yieldlove GmbH on behalf of Astrodienst.

**\+ See the privacy policy of Yieldlove GmbH, from 05.11.2018**

**Updates and changes of the Privacy Policy**

This page is updated and modified from time to time. Last Update: 15 May 2018. By visiting www.astro.com and by using its services, you declare that you accept our Data Protection Policy and Terms of Use.

The original data protection declaration is in German. The translated versions are for better comprehension only. In case of disputes, the German text takes precedence.

**Contact**

Astrodienst AG  
Dammstrasse 23  
8702 Zollikon / Zürich  
Switzerland

Telephone international: +41-44-392 18 18  
Telephone within Switzerland: 044-392 18 18  
(Mo - Fr 09-12h und 14 - 17h, Swiss time)

Email for questions regarding privacy and data deletion: [userdata@astro.com](mailto:userdata@astro.com)

EU representative for Astrodienst and Astro AG:  
C. Treindl  
Turmstr. 47  
DE-72351 Geislingen-Binsdorf

Email: [eu_vertretung@astro.ch](mailto:eu_vertretung@astro.ch)

Sources: Disclaimer eRecht24, DGD Deutsche Gesellschaft für Datenschutz GmbH, Privacy Policies Google Adsense / Google Analytics / Twitter / Criteo / Facebook
